[
  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "Packet Counter Service",
    "Problem": "Counting carrier packets on the Dolv3 web client created excessive database load, leading to slow page load time and reduced database performance",
    "Solution":"Creation of microservice to perform packet counting in memory and store the count in the database",
    "Result": ["Packet count webpage load time decreased from 30 seconds to under one second",
       "Eliminated over 3 million database operations per page instance per minute, significantly reducing database strain leading to system-wide performance increases",
        "Improved code quality by moving business logic out of the user interface and database" ]
  },

  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "HTML5 Pilot Project",
    "Problem": "Our current website, Dolv3, is running on the Silverlight platform. Silverlight will be discontinued by major web browsers in the near future, requiring us to build a replacement",
    "Solution":"Development of prototype website utilizing modern web technologies. We decided to use the MEAN stack supplemented by Windows microservices",
    "Result": ["Improved load time of corresponding pages from 4 seconds to under 300 milliseconds",
      "Enhanced user experience though modernization of user interface",
      "Produced quality code in line with current best practices, encouraging code readability, reuse, and extensibility",
      "Validated code correctness through array of unit and integration tests",
      "Established continuous integration environment to build and test code upon pull requests" ]
  },

  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "Token Authentication Service",
    "Problem": "Users on the prototype replacement for Dolv3 require secure authentication to access the site",
    "Solution":"Development of token-based authentication microservice using ASP.NET WebAPI and MongoDB",
    "Result": ["Improved security over basic authentication by negating the need to send user credentials through the request header",
       "Achieved authentication request time of approximately 60 milliseconds",
       "Provided automatic token invalidation through time and IP based checks",
       "Facilitated customization of token rules through minimal and complete interface",
       "Designed basic safeguards to mitigate malicious logins by counting failed attempts"]
  },

  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "User Data Service",
    "Problem": "User information stored in SQL servers must be made available to several parts of our prototype website",
    "Solution":"Development of REST microservice to allow others services to request information about specific users",
    "Result": ["Allowed services to retrieve user data without making SQL calls",
      "Enabled system to serve data only belonging to that user, ensuring data privacy"]
  },

  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "Asset Summary Service",
    "Problem": "Entire asset summary is periodically being cached into MongoDB from SQL, but services only require specific parts of result set",
    "Solution":"Development of microservice to read through stored asset summary and retrieve records correlated with the given identification key",
    "Result": ["Reduced data retrieval time of 2200 records from approximately 4 seconds to under 400 milliseconds compared to Silverlight system",
      "Improved load time of user interface by serving preformatted data"]
  },
  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "DOL Rest Service",
    "Problem": "Having several server-side microservices on different routes complicates REST calls from the client",
    "Solution":"Development of microservice which encapsulates server-side services and exposes a single interface  ",
    "Result": ["Simplified creation of REST calls to the backend through a coherent interface, leading to simpler and more consistent code",
      "Prevented unauthorized access to microservices by only publicizing routes needed by the client ",
      "Enhanced logging features through centralization of server traffic",
      "Allowed prototype application to operate over a single firewall port, improving system security",
      "Provided functionality to combine REST calls into a single route, reducing the amount of work performed on the client"]
  },
  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "Mongo Access Layer",
    "Problem": "Services require an abstraction through which to interact with MongoDB",
    "Solution":"Development of data access layer allowing services to perform CRUD operations with their business objects",
    "Result": ["Reduced coupling with the database by separating implementation of the database from business logic",
      "Promoted code reusability by engineering solution with generic type arguments",
      "Enabled modification of database operations without impacting the business logic code",
      "Bolstered functionality of CRUD operations by supporting LINQ queries in function arguments"]
  },
  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "Baidu Maps",
    "Problem": "Customers in China are unable to access our Google Maps application due to government restrictions",
    "Solution":"Development of Baidu Maps clone of our Google Maps application",
    "Result": ["Achieved core functionality on the Baidu platform, enabling blocked customers utilize our mapping data",
      "Cleaned up code before writing new features, reducing pollution of the global namespace, improving readability, reliability and performance",
      "Organized mapping code into duck-typed interface, accommodating Baidu without needing to rewrite underlying business logic" ]
  },
  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "WiX Installer",
    "Problem": "Windows Installer, our current installation method, is incompatible with services created in Visual Studio 2013",
    "Solution":"Development and documentation of WiX Installer construction process",
    "Result": ["Produced a highly customizable WiX installer compatible with our existing build and deployment process",
      "Documented the creation process, enabling team members to create their own installers",
      "Programmed custom XML transform to remove duplicates from WiX's file harvest, eliminating compiler errors caused by its use"]
  },
  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "IIS Publish Script",
    "Problem": "Current method of publishing IIS packages by hand is tedious and error-prone",
    "Solution":"Development of PowerShell script for automating publish package deployment",
    "Result": ["Overcame obstacles hindering previous developers tasked with this problem",
      "Furthererd automation of deployment process, reducing the chance of user error"]
    }
  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "Build Script Overhaul",
    "Problem": "Build script updates require a manual push to the build machine to take effect",
    "Solution":"Development of PowerShell script which is able to execute build scripts included in repository clones",
    "Result": ["Eliminated need for developers to manually update the builder when a new solution is added",
      "Boosted flexibility of build process by allowing custom builds to be run without any machine changes",
      "Reduced amount of code needed by build machines" ]
  },
  {
    "jobId": ["dataonline"],
    "Name": "Automated Billing",
    "Problem": "Processing of billing records is executed by hand with an outdated Visual Basic script",
    "Solution":"Development of Windows Service to process billing records ",
    "Result": ["Significantly reduced amount of time spent to process billing records",
      "Constructed PowerShell script to invoke billing service as a scheduled task, ensuring billing records are always up to date"]
    },
    {
      "jobId": ["dataonline"],
      "Name": "Helium ISO Design Curve",
      "Problem": "Customers viewing a pressure graph of their helium ISO container need to know how their tank is performing",
      "Solution":"Development of data visualization graph displaying the expected behavior of a tank",
      "Result": ["Reverse-engineered equations from graphs provided by tank manufacturers, resulting in an accurate data visualization",
        "Designed user interface features for efficiently configuring equation parameters",
        "Demonstrated by company owners at ITCO 2015" ]
    }
]
